（カカシ）敵の気配が消えた。
There's no sign of the enemy.
（ガイ）味方も見当たらないが
戦力が散りすぎている。
I don't see our forces either.
We're too scattered.
各部隊を集結させるべきだろう。
We must gather the troops together.
You're right.
そうだな。
カカシ隊長。
Captain Kakashi!
ユルイの部隊から救援要請です。
Yurui's unit is requesting
reinforcements!
オモイがいる部隊か…
どうした？
Omoi's in that unit.
What's up?
現在　林檎雨由利と
交戦中とのことです。
They're engaged in a fight
with Ameyuri Ringo!
林檎雨由利…。
Ameyuri Ringo…
忍刀七人衆
雷刀　牙の使い手か。
One of the Seven
Ninja Swordsmen
who wields
the Lightning Blade, Fang…
俺が行く。
俺も行こう。
I'll go!
I'm going too.
林檎雨由利は　雷遁使いだ。
Ameyuri Ringo uses
the Lightning Style.
俺の雷遁で
相殺できるかもしれない。
I may be able to neutralize her
with my own Lightning Style.
The Lightning Blade:
Ameyuri Ringo!
（雨由利）みんな隠れてないで。
Stop hiding!
誰か私のハートを
ビビっとさせるヤツはいないの？
Isn't there anyone here that can send
shockwaves through my heart?
雷遁　雷牙！
Lightning Style: Lighting Fang!
臆病者はタイプじゃないよ。
Cowards aren't my type!
（ユルイ）まだ増援は来ないのか？
Where are the reinforcements?!
お仕置きに
全員　黒焦げにしてあげる。
As punishment…
I'm going to burn you to a crisp!
雷遁　サンダーゲート！
Lighting Style: Thunder Gate!
うわ～！
（ヌルイ）ユルイ！
Yurui!
Hang on, Yurui!
しっかりしろ　ユルイ！
（ユルイ）ダメだ…
もう暗くなってきてやがる…。
It's over…
Everything's…going dark…
あきらめるな　ユルイ。
もうすぐ増援が来るぞ。
Don't give up, Yurui!
Help is on the way!
Nurui… It's in…
your hands now…
ヌルイ　あとを　頼んだ…。
ユルイ　ユルイ！
Yurui! Yurui!
（オモイ）くそっ　もううんざりだ。
Damn it! I've had it with this!
何人死んだんだ！
How many have died already?
これが　戦争なのかよ…。
Is this what war is?!
生き残ったのは
たったこれだけか。
Are we the only survivors?
どうやら　そのようですね。
It looks that way.
これからは　俺が指揮をとる。
I'll take command from now on.
この中じゃ
俺がいちばん先輩だからな。
I have seniority here.
（カユイ）林檎雨由利は
別方向の小隊を追ってった。
Ameyuri Ringo went after
the other platoon
in the other direction.
すぐに戻ってくるぞ。
But she'll be back.
早く　どうするか決めないと。
We have to decide
what to do quickly.
それは決まってる　退却だ。
It's obvious. We retreat.
逃げ出すんですか？
Are we running away?
たかだか忍刀１人に。
Just because she's one of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen?
Are you suggesting we take on
Ameyuri Ringo?
まさか　林檎雨由利と
やりあおうなんてこと→
言い出すんじゃねえだろうな。
それは…。
Well…
お前らしくねえな　オモイ。
That's not like you, Omoi.
お前は　俺と同じ
慎重派だと思ってたんだが。
I thought you were
the cautious type, just like me.
War is not the place
for revenge.
戦争は　敵討ちの場じゃねえ。
それに忍刀と俺たちが
やりあったって→
And besides,
we don't have a chance
勝てるわけねえだろ。
アイツらは　象か虎。
against someone with
a Ninja Blade.
They are like elephants and tigers.
We're mere ants.
俺たちは　ただのアリンコだ。
じゃあ　何のために
俺たちは　いるんです？
Then why the hell are we here?!
うぬぼれるな　オモイ
英雄にでもなったつもりか？
Don't get full of yourself, Omoi.
Are you trying to be a hero now?
とにかく　ここの指揮官は俺だ。
In any case, I'm the leader now!
林檎雨由利を牽制しつつ
撤退する。
We'll create a diversion for
Ameyuri Ringo and make our escape.
つまんないの
誰も私を　ビビッとさせてくれない。
How boring… Not a single soul
to give me a thrill.
そういえば　まだ　向こうに
２～３匹　残ってたっけ。
Oh, that's right.
There were two or three
more back there.
私のタイプいないかなぁ？
Maybe they're more my type.
先ほど見えた落雷。
That flash of lightning earlier…
林檎雨由利の雷遁の術に
間違いなさそうだな。
There's no doubt it was
Ameyuri Ringo's Lightning Style.
Damage of this scope,
in an instant.
一瞬でこの広範囲を…。
これでは　中忍クラスが
１００人がかりでも勝てまい。
Not even a hundred chunin
could defeat her.
Well, who knows…
わからないよ
こんなときだからこそ→
In a desperate moment like this,
隠れた英雄が
出るかもしれない。
a hero could rise up
from among them.
散り散りになった小隊たちに→
Wishing for the survival of
our scattered comrades
生きててほしいという
気持はわかるがな→
is one thing.
現状を見ると
今は気休めにしか聞こえん。
Hoping for a hero is
just wishful thinking.
とにかく戦いの跡からして
林檎雨由利は北上してる。
Whatever the case,
judging from the traces of battle,
Ameyuri Ringo is headed north.
その先に　生き残りがいるはずだ。
急ごう！
There should be survivors
beyond that.
Let's hurry!
《クソッ！　このまま　どんどん逃げて
結局　世界一周しちまって→
Damn it… If we keep running
and running…
Pretty soon,
we'll circle the globe.
何周も　何周も逃げ回るうちに→
And if we keep circling
the globe over and over again,
なんで戦いを続けてんのかも
忘れて→
we'll forget why the hell
we're fighting.
誰も俺が生きているなんて
思わなくなって…。
And no one will think
that I'm still alive.
俺は　ただ死ぬまで
ずっと逃げ続けてて…。
I'll keep running and
running until I die.
そんなことなら　いっそ…》
If that's the case, then…
隊長　まだ退却を
続けるつもりなんですか？
Captain! Are we still gonna
keep running away?
逃げていれば　援軍が来て→
If we keep running,
maybe the reinforcements will arrive
ヤツを　なんとかしてくれるかも
しれねえ。
and take care of that bitch.
《チッ　他力本願かよ》
Waiting for others to bail us out?!
何やってるんですか？
What are you doing?
逃げるっつっても
戦った体裁はとっとかねえと→
We have to make it look
like we put up a fight…
戦争が終わったとき
何言われるか　わからねえからな。
Otherwise, who knows what
they'll say after the war.
《くだらねえ　見栄かよ。
How stupid. Talk about ego…
それに　こんなバレバレの罠。
And this trap is so obvious!
敵に俺たちの逃げている方向を
知らせるようなもんだぜ。
It's like telling the enemy exactly
which way we're running.
やっぱり　コイツなんかに
ついていったら→
Nothing good's gonna come
from following this guy!
ろくなことにならねえ》
《フフフ！　私から逃げようったって
無理なんだから》
You can't run away from me.
何よ　この罠！
They call this a trap?
They must think I'm stupid.
私のこと　ナメてるわけ？
絶対に逃がさないんだから！
I'm never going to let you go!
そもそも　林檎雨由利ってのは
どんなヤツなんです？
Just who is
this Ameyuri Ringo anyway?
雷遁使いの天才と呼ばれた女だ。
A woman known to be an exceptional user
of the Lightning Style.
Although she died young
from an incurable disease,
不治の病で早死にしたらしいが→
狙った獲物は
絶対に逃がさなかったって噂だ。
it's said she never lost her prey.
逃げ切れない相手？
There's no escaping her?
余計なことを言うな　カユイ！
That's enough, Kayui!
ヌルイ…　アンタそれがわかってて！
Nurui!
You knew this, and still…
来たぞ！
Here she comes!
Damn it!
She's faster than I thought.
クソッ！　思ってたより速かったな。
《そら追いつかれるさ。
こんなヌルイことしてたら！》
Of course, she's gonna catch up!
This is such a lame strategy!
おおっ！
うわっ！
♪～
逃げ切れない！
We can't outrun her!
Let's fight!
戦いましょう！
いいや　ダメだ！
No! It's no use!
それじゃ　いつまで
逃げるつもりなんです？
How far can we run?!
She always gets her prey, right?!
ヤツからは　逃げ切れないんでしょ！
I know!
そんなことはわかってる！
Well, do you know that our lives
are in your hands?!
わかってるって…。
俺たちの命はな
アンタにかかってるんだぞ！
だから退却している。
That's why we're retreating!
アンタ　それで忍か！
How can you call yourself
a shinobi?!
Have you even thought about
our fallen comrades?!
死んでった仲間のことを
考えたことがあるのか！
オモイ！　お前はヌルイを誤解してる。
Omoi! You don't understand Nurui!
ヌルイ！　アンタもアンタだ！
And Nurui, you too!
Why don't…?!
どうして…。
（ヌルイ）黙れカユイ！
Shut up, Kayui!
俺は…　もう逃げるなんて
ごめんだ！
I've…
had enough of running!
オモイ…。
Omoi…
知ってるんだぜ　ヌルイ。
I know…about your reputation
in the village, Nurui.
里での　アンタの評判くらい。
オモイ！　そのへんにしとけ！
Omoi! That's enough!
アンタは　慎重なふりしてる
臆病者だって。
That you being cautious is
just to hide your cowardice!
俺は慎重派だが　臆病者じゃねえ！
Well, I'm a cautious guy,
but I'm no coward!
やめろ　オモイ！
今　戦っても　ムダだ。
Stop it, Omoi!
Fighting is useless right now!
俺たちは　英雄になるなんてことは
できねえんだよ！
We can't be heroes!
The thought didn't even
cross my mind!
そんなこと言われなくても
わかってますよ！
でも　ずっと　ちらつくんだ。
I just keep seeing Yurui's face
as he was dying!
さっき死んでった　ユルイの顔が。
たとえ逃げのびたって→
And even if we escape somehow,
I can't go on living with
that image
俺は　そんなものを見続けながら
生きていくなんて　ごめんだ！
constantly flashing
through my mind.
Stop it, Omoi!
やめろ　オモイ
今　戦ってもムダだ。
Fighting is useless right now!
俺たちは英雄になるなんてことは
できねえんだよ。
We can't be heroes!
そんなこと　言われなくても
わかってますよ！
The thought didn't even
cross my mind!
でも　ずっと　ちらつくんだ。
I just keep seeing Yurui's face
as he was dying!
さっき死んでった
ユルイの顔が。
例え　逃げのびたって→
And even if we escape somehow,
俺は　そんなものを見続けながら
生きていくなんてごめんだ。
I can't go on living with
that image
constantly flashing
through my mind.
オモイ！
Omoi!
どうやら　まだ林檎雨由利は
誰かを追っているようだ。
Looks like Ameyuri Ringo is
still in pursuit of someone.
でも　まずいね。
This isn't good…
この先に
忍連合の部隊は誰もいない。
There aren't any Allied Shinobi
units beyond this point.
追われてる側は
ますます孤立するだけだ。
The pursued are only making
themselves more isolated.
急ごう！
Let's hurry!
うお～！
や～ん　いるじゃない。
Oh, here's one.
私に向かってきてくれる人が。
Someone who's willing to face me!
ユルイの敵！
I'm avenging Yurui!
なに？　もう逃げ出しちゃうの？
What? Running away so soon?
結局　この程度…。
You were so worthless after—!
なんてな
雲流　騙し斬り！
Fooled ya!
Cloud Style: Deception Slice!
って　騙されるか！
No one tricks me!
雷刀術　落雷！
Lightning Blade Jutsu!
Thunderbolt!
うお～！
《強え…　コイツに勝つには→
She's strong…
If I'm gonna beat her,
ビー様に教わった
あれを使うしか》
I have to use the one
Bee taught me!
((ビー：俺の剣術自慢。
My sword technique is
one to behold!
チケット１万
さばいてくれたら　俺のど自慢。
If you get 10,000 tickets sold,
and if you come and watch me rap
I'll help put your skill on the map.
お前だって　腕自慢。
それで本当に　ビー様。
You'll really teach me
your lethal blade technique?
教えてくれるんでしょうね？
必殺の剣。
((っつうか
雲隠れに１万人もいるのか？))
Hey, are there really 10,000 guys
in the Hidden Cloud?
はっきりズバリ　お前の剣術
パワーもキレも　中のチュー。
To put it bluntly,
your sword power and skill
ain't too much of a thrill.
俺は　ラップに夢中のチュー。
Unlike my rapping
which keeps feet a-stomping.
つまり俺は
まるで普通だってことですか？
In other words, you are saying
I'm average?
だけど騙し斬りだけ　センスキラリ。
Except your Deception Slice
which is divine.
それを　ノラリクラリ伸ばす展開
それが　俺の限界。
So polish that up and you'll be fine.
Now this lesson is at
the end of the line.
ようするに　俺の裏斬りを
もっと工夫するわけですね？
So you're telling me to tweak
my Deception Slice and make it better?
(イエー))
Yeah!
《それが　この術
裏霞斬り》
And the result of that is…
Hidden Mist Slice.
また向かってくる気？
Still not giving up?
ちょっとは
骨がありそうじゃない。
At least you have some backbone.
《この剣は　どこから出てくるか
太刀筋を読ませない剣》
This sword style makes it difficult
to read the path of the blade!
ワオ！
《この術の本気はここからだ》
I'm just beginning to
execute this jutsu!
My personal style…
Hidden Mist Slice, Kai!
《俺流　裏霞斬り改》
Let's see you counter this!
（オモイ）これならかわせねえ！
Huh? They're all decoys?!
（雨由利）全部オトリ？
とった！
Gotcha!
雷遁　爆雷！
Lightning Style! Depth Charge!
うわ！
けっこうやるわね。
You're not bad at all.
普通の人なら
やられてたけど→
Most guys would be dead.
ごめんね　私すんごく強くって。
Sorry, but I'm really strong.
Omoi!
（ヌルイ）オモイ！
今は殺さないでいてあげる。
I won't kill you just yet.
Because I'm the type of person
だって私　好きなものは
最後に食べるタイプなの。
who saves the things
I like to eat for last.
来るな！　ヌルイ　カユイ！
Don't come!
Nurui! Kayui!
ヌルイ…。
Nurui…
ヌルイ　大丈夫か　ヌルイ？
Nurui!
Are you all right, Nurui?!
この　余計なことしやがって。
Did you have to act so foolishly?
すまない　俺のために。
I'm sorry… For my sake…
そうさ　全部ぶち壊しだぜ。
Damn right. Everything's ruined.
いいか　よく聞け　オモイ。
Now listen carefully…
Omoi…
見つけた！
Found you!
I won't let you get away.
逃がさないんだから。
It's no good…
I don't feel like I can win!
《ダメだ　勝てる気がしねえ。
つうか　俺じゃ勝てねえ！》
More like, I can't beat her!
大丈夫か　カユイ！
はい。
Are you all right, Kayui?!
Yes…
他に　まだ誰かいるのか？
Is there anyone else with you?
ヌルイとオモイが　この先に。
Nurui and Omoi are up ahead…
林檎雨由利も　そこか。
Ameyuri Ringo is there too, huh?
そこで　ヤツを仕留めます。
And they're going to
bring her down.
《ヌルイの言うとおりだ！
Nurui was right.
俺には最初から
逃げるしか方法はなかった！
Running away was my only option!
俺は英雄じゃねえ！
なんて　バカだったんだ　俺は》
I'm no hero!
How could I have been so stupid?!
ぐわ～っ！
さあ　覚悟はいい？
Now then, are you prepared?
わかったよ。
やりゃいいんだろ　やりゃ！
Fine… You want me to fight?
I'll fight then.
その努力は認めてあげるわ。
You're determined.
I'll give you that.
《間に合ってくれよ！》
Please let us get there in time!
コイツは俺が　いや　俺たちが
倒さなきゃいけねえんだ！
I have to, I mean,
we have to bring her down.
ヌルイ…　ユルイ！
Nurui… Yurui…
Bring me down?
私を倒すなんて
まだ　そんな寝言　言ってるの？
Are you still talking nonsense?
テメエなんか
最初からなめてんだよ！
I planned to lick you
from the beginning!
'Cuz my flavor today is apple candy
and your name means just that!
なんつったって
今日の飴は林檎味だからな！
来いよ　お前の渾身の術で！
Bring it on with
your strongest jutsu!
うお～っ！
Too bad!
And you were my type too.
残念！　せっかく
私好みの男だったのに。
雷遁　サンダーゲート！
Lightning Style: Thunder Gate!
何これ！？
What is this?!
私を罠に？
You trapped me?!
This is actually a bottomless marsh.
ここは　もともと底なし沼だ。
Once you're stuck,
you'll never get out.
一度はまったら
出られることはねえ。
でも私の道連れに
なってくれるなんて　ステキ。
And you're coming with me?
What a gentleman!
((ユルイは　俺の親友だった。
Yurui was my friend.
公私混同してたのは俺さ。
I'm the one who let
personal feelings interfere.
I wanted to avenge Yurui…
俺は　ユルイの敵を…。
俺たちでヤツを倒す方法は
たった１つしかなかった。
There was only one way
for us to beat her.
この先に底なし沼がある。
There is a bottomless marsh
up ahead.
It's been covered with
an Earth Style lid.
そこには土遁の蓋がしてある。
If she uses her Lightning Style there,
そこでヤツが雷遁を使えば
ヤツは底なし沼に沈む。
she'll sink into
this bottomless marsh.
そこにヤツを引っ張り込む
作戦だった。
I planned to lure her there.
大戦に向けて　あらかじめ
俺とユルイとカユイで→
Yurui, Kayui and I had made
a number of traps
in preparation for a big battle.
いくつかの罠を作っておいたんだ。
それじゃあ　アンタ
逃げてたわけじゃ…。
So you…weren't running away?
オモイ　俺は自分の力量を知ってる。
Omoi, I know the limits
of my strength.
But my plan won't work.
You must run away.
だが　この計画は　もうなしだ。
逃げろ。
I'll stop Ameyuri Ringo here.
林檎雨由利は
俺がここで食い止める。
そんな体じゃ無理だ！
You can't in your condition!
それにヤツからは
どうせ逃げられないんだろ？
And besides, there's no
running away from her, right?!
(やめろ　オモイ！))
Stop… Omoi…
オモイ！
Omo
カカシさん　ガイさん！
なんとか間に合ったようだな。
引っ張り上げろ！
私と一緒に
逝ってくれるんじゃないの？
残念だが　またの機会にするよ。
今度　生まれ変わったら
好きなものは最初に食べるわ。
もうアンタが
生まれ変わることはねえ。
これは餞別だ。
ありがとう。
オモイ　俺の名はオモイだ。
オモイ…。
それは　お礼よ。
あの世で待ってるわ。
よくやった　オモイ。
お前は英雄だ。
本当の英雄は　アンタだよ。
やっぱり　いるもんだな
常に新しい英雄ってのが。
いつ見ても　いいもんだ
男の熱い友情は。
（いのいち）カカシ　ガイ　聞いてくれ。
お前たちには先に連絡しておく。
今　ナルトとビーが戦場に向かっている。
我々の説得も
ナルトには効かなかったようだ。
だが　これを機会に
戦況を一気に立て直す。
以上だ。
聞いたか？　カカシ。
あぁ
とうとう動き出したようだね。
俺たちが待ちかねていた
英雄たちも。